### **NEHA GUPTA**

House No. 267, 2<sup>nd</sup> Floor, Sector 51, Gurgoan Mobile: (+91)813-092-0165 Email: neha200@gmail.com

Total Experience: 8 Years

### **Professional Summary:**

Driven QA / Test Manager with experience delivering large scale staff augmentation testing services, continuous improvement and innovation, change management, proofs of concept, and resource management for more than 8 years. Expertise in the field Software Quality Assurance (QC), Manual and Automation testing with a wide variety of projects and environments, which include Client server, webbased application and database related projects on Windows and Unix operating systems. Possess extensive experience in creation and execution of QA Testing Processes, Test Strategies, Test Plans, Test Cases, Bug Documentation, Procedure and excellent Analytical Skills coupled with good communication and interpersonal skills describing a committed team player; currently aspiring for a challenging position in Quality Assurance Managerial Position.

### **Professional Expertise:**

- In depth knowledge of entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Software Test Life Cycle (STLC).
- Extensive experience in testing of various industries using tools like Quality Center/ALM, Test Director, JIRA, Quick Test Professional and SQL.
- Expertise in analyzing Business Requirements, System Requirements And Functional Requirement Specification, Develop System Test Plan, Test Strategies And Test Cases.
- Well-versed with software QA testing procedures. Actively participated in all type of reviews including Requirement, Test cases, Test log and Defects.
- Strong testing Quality Assurance experience within agile environment as well as Waterfall.
- Extensively worked in all phase of testing includes Smoke, Functional, Regression, System, and User Acceptance Testing (UAT).
- Basic Experience with Automation Testing Tools using Quick Test Professional (QTP).
- Experience in writing and executing SQL queries for Data Verification, Data Validation And Data Integrity.
- Communicate effectively with project Managers, Development and Testing team throughout the Software Test Life Cycle (STLC) to provide clear objectives and report on progress and issues in a timely manner.
- Have good documentation skills in creating Test Cases, Defect Reports and Test completion reports.
- Extensively written Test Analysis Report (TAR).
- Ability to handle multiple projects with competing deadlines in a fast paced environment.
- Excellent interpersonal and customer relational skills,
- Organized, attention to details, self-motivation, personable, multi-focused and ability to meet project milestones and deliverable dates.
- Possess excellent interpersonal, written, verbal communication skills and strong analytical, problem solving, decision-making skills.
- Ability to work independently as well as a team successfully.
- Quick learner, capable to learn new system, software & hardware technology quickly.

### **Education:**

Master's in Computer Application-2009 and Bachelors in Computer Application-2006 from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, New Delhi, India.

### **Technical Skills:**

Operating system : Windows 2000/2003/2007 Windows XP/Vista/Linux Mac and UNIX

Programming Languages : VB, C, HTML, Java, XML

Tools : Quick test Professional, JAMA and Mercury Quality center,

PL/SQL,SOAP UI,

LDAP, TOPS Mainframe system, Emulator (IPhone & Android),

Simulator (IPhone,

Android & Blackberry)

Defect tracking tools : Test director, JIRA and Bugzilla

RDBMS/Database : Oracle, SQL server, DB2 and MS Access

Software Methodologies : Waterfall, V model

Web Browsers : Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Netscape, Opera, Google chrome.

MS Office : MS Word, MS Excel, MS Power Point, MS Outlook.

### **Professional Experiences:**

# ${\bf RM\ METALS, NEW\ JERSEY, USA}$

**February 2015 – August 2017** 

**QA Delivery Manager** 

In this, I started working as Quality Assurance Analyst. Knowledge of financial, retail, transportation and Import/Export were the multiple areas for which created an in-house web based tool for the organization. I have gain lots of experience during this project. Most of my responsibilities were to execute and review the test cases, and Report bug using Quality Center. Work closely with the developer and different departments to fix the existing bug.

### Responsibilities:

- Developed/reviewed unit test cases, configured environments and prepared test data for testing.
- Performed data quality test to determine whether processed data is correctly extracted, transformed and loaded
- Extensively used T-SQL to verify and validate the data loaded to the SQL Server 2005
- Worked with T-SQL for validating the SQL Server 2000 data.
- Wrote and implemented test plan, various test cases & test scripts.
- Performed Functionality, Stress, Security, and GUI& Regression testing of web-based applications.
- Co-ordinate testing efforts between onsite and offshore teams.
- Worked with Production environment to resolve several data issues.
- Experience in integration of various data sources with Multiple Relational Databases like Oracle, SQL Server, MS Excel, MS Access and Flat Files.
- Tested several reports and automated using Quick Test Pro.
- Wrote several Stored Procedures and modified existing stored procedures.
- Was involved with extraction routines to verify all the required data loaded into target systems.
- Extensively executed SQL queries in order to view successful transactions of data and for validating data.
- Analyzed business requirements, use case documents, functional specs & assisted QA team lead in writing the test plans.
- As a Test Lead Created Test plan, Test scenarios and test cases.
- Was involved in analyzing scope of testing the application. Test Strategy was created to test the all modules of the Data Warehouse.
- Created the test data for interpreting positive/negative results during functional testing.
- Was involved in the whole testing life cycle covering the entire project from initiation to completion
- Clearly communicated and documented test results and defect resolution during all phases of testing.
- Prepared test cases by understanding the business requirements, Data Mapping documents and technical specifications.

- Designed and directed the preparation of test data; prepared test data, documented detailed results, provided regular and ad-hoc test reports.
- Experienced in data analysis and data testing. Verified fields present in the reports are as agreed in the ETL specifications.
- Was extensively involved with backend testing by writing complex SQL queries.
- Worked closely with the development teams to replicate end user issues.

Environment: Quality Center, Quick Test Pro (QTP), SQL server, Visual Basic, ASP, ActiveX Controls, Windows XP, XML, Oracle, MS Office (Word/Excel)

### A Xerox Company, Noida, India Qauality Analyst

**June 2012 - September 2014** 

As being my first health care project with Xerox turned out to be a great experienced for me. Most of my responsibilities were to create scenario, scenario to test cases from business requirement designed. I was also responsible for testing the XML. I have compile report from team members and send it to the responsible team lead.

#### Responsibilities:

- Created Test Strategy and Test cases for the testing effort.
- Responsible for finding the indicators and writing the test scripts for testing the test cases.
- Conducted Smoke, Non Functional, Functional, System, Regression and Integration testing.
- Developed SQL to achieve the data transformations.
- Tested the created SSIS packages to transfer data from various sources like Oracle, Excel,
- Worked with **SSIS system** variable, passing variables between packages.
- Perform black box and white box testing by designing and constructing test cases, test data and test
  execution.
- Conducted Black Box Functional, Regression and Data Driven. White box Unit and Integration Testing (positive and negative scenarios).
- Performed black box/functional testing, regression testing on Application under Test.
- Used T-SQL for Querying the SQL Server2000 database for data validation and data conditioning.
- Performed back-end testing on the Oracle, DB2 and Teradata databases by writing SQL queries
- Conducted backend testing using SQL Assistant.
- Based on the business requirements, created Test Plan, Test Cases, and Test Script documents to test the Business Objects reports.
- Responsible for testing all four entities Group Batch, Group Real-time, Member Batch and Member Real-time.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings with the management team
- Created test cases for both Batch and Real-time Processes.
- Responsible for testing the CDC for both Member and Group Real-time process.
- Used Trillium for Data cleansing and data matching purpose.
- Also responsible for testing the staging tables and Look-up spreadsheet.
- Used Control-M for scheduling the jobs.
- Conducted Weekly **Onsite-Offshore Status** Meetings.
- Used Axis tool for comparing the XML's.
- Worked on UNIX commands and shell scripting for scheduling the jobs from command line.
- Developed shell scripts for finding the XML's for each member from the files.
- Worked with clients to demonstrate agile techniques for software development, explained and implemented unit testing, created coding standards based on IBM recommendations.
- Performed Quality Analysis on problem reports against software and the production system in order to confirm that problems truly exists and can be recreated for testing
- Responsible for executing the test cases for Batch and Real-time that included both Member and Group data.
- Executed the scenarios and analyzed the results through monitors and graphs.
- Actively communicated with the end users and business users to create realistic test cases.

- Tracked bugs using Quality Centre and generate the defect reports from the Dashboard module for review by the development team
- Batch testing development and execution and done analysis of batch works.
- Participated in various meetings and discussed Enhancement Request issues.
- Review the test cases written based on the Change Request document.
- Testing has been done based on Change Requests and Defect Requests.
- Conducted Regression testing after the bugs have been fixed by the development team
- Generated reports from Quality Center.
- Responsible for source control, versioning, and configuration management of test scripts, test results, defects
- Actively participated in various meetings like defect resolution meeting, QA status, Knowledge transfer meeting.

**Environment:** SQL, PL/SQL, Teradata 12.0,DB2, TOAD 9.2, Oracle 10g,Teradata V2R6, SQL Assistant, XML, XML Spy 2008, Java, HP Quality Center 10.0, MS Access, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, Microsoft Share Point, Unix Shell Scripting, Windows NT/XP//2003

## Mckinsey & Company (Infotech Global India), Gurgaon, India November 2010 - May 2012 Quality Analyst Specialist

Employee Performance Review (EPR) and 360 degree feedback is an application that provides each employee the opportunity to receive performance feedback from his or her supervisor and four to eight peers, reporting staff members, coworkers and customers. Most 360 degree feedback tools are also responded to by each individual in a self-assessment. 360 degree feedback allows each individual to understand how his effectiveness as an employee, coworker, or staff member is viewed by others. Most of my responsibilities were to attend daily meeting, Execute test cases, and Report bug using Quality Center. Work closely with the developer to fix the existing bug.

### Responsibilities:

- Developed unit test cases, configured environments and prepared test data for testing.
- Performed data quality test to determine whether processed data is correctly extracted, transformed and loaded.
- Extensively used T-SOL to verify and validate the data loaded to the SOL Server 2005
- Worked with T-SQL for validating the SQL Server 2000 data.
- Wrote and implemented test plan, various test cases & test scripts.
- Performed Functionality, Stress, Security, and GUI& Regression testing of web-based applications.
- Co-ordinate testing efforts between onsite and offshore teams.
- Worked with Production environment to resolve several data issues.
- Experience in integration of various data sources with Multiple Relational Databases like Oracle, SQL Server, MS Excel, MS Access and Flat Files.
- Tested several reports and automated using Quick Test Pro.
- Wrote several Stored Procedures and modified existing stored procedures.
- Was involved with extraction routines to verify all the required data loaded into target systems.
- Extensively executed SQL queries in order to view successful transactions of data and for validating data.
- Functioned as the Onsite / Offshore coordinator and Team Lead
- Analyzed business requirements, use case documents, functional specs & assisted QA team lead in writing the test plans.
- As a Test Lead Created Test plan, Test scenarios and test cases.
- Was involved in analyzing scope of testing the application. Test Strategy was created to test the all modules of the Data Warehouse.
- Created the test data for interpreting positive/negative results during functional testing.
- Was involved in the whole testing life cycle covering the entire project from initiation to completion
- Clearly communicated and documented test results and defect resolution during all phases of testing.

- Prepared test cases by understanding the business requirements, Data Mapping documents and technical specifications.
- Designed and directed the preparation of test data; prepared test data, documented detailed results, provided regular and ad-hoc test reports.
- Experienced in data analysis and data testing. Verified fields present in the reports are as agreed in the ETL specifications.
- Was extensively involved with backend testing by writing complex SQL queries.
- Worked closely with the development teams to replicate end user issues.

**Environment:** Quality Center, Quick Test Pro (QTP), SQL server, Visual Basic, ASP, ActiveX Controls, Windows XP, XML, Oracle, MS Office (Word/Excel)

### National Infomatic Centre, New Delhi , India Jr. Assistant Programmer

**May 2010 - November 2010** 

GAMS is an automated Web based system that takes care about the house allotment, cancellation, generating vacancy list, acceptance, regularization etc. There are more than 90,000 quarters and hostel units under General Pool. The software will have functional modules for most of the common activities in respect of Government Accommodation. It will keep information about the Housing Stock, Occupants of the Government Houses, Vacation of the Houses, Registration of new applicants, Allotment of the houses on regular and discretionary basis, Monthly recovery of license fees, Subletting and litigation cases, Historical data and all other matters related with accommodation in Delhi, Kolkata, Chennai, Mumbai and Faridabad, Govt. of Delhi & Parliament House.

NIC has developed a website hosted at <a href="http://www.estates.nic.in">http://www.estates.nic.in</a> for Directorate of Estates where government employees can know about their allotment status of government accommodation.

### Responsibilities:

- Analyzing the entire procedure of the system. (Oracle 10g Forms & Reports, SQL and PL/SQL.)
- Designing and Testing of the application along with Development & implementation using Java/J2EE,
   SQL.
- Selecting appropriate data as per functionality & test it against the functional specifications in order to check for normal and abnormal behavior of the system.
- Create Test Plan and Test Cases. (Designing and Testing of the application along with Development & implementation using Java/J2EE, SQL.)
- Responsible for monitoring and maintaining quality and compliance targets Defines and tracks
  quality assurance metrics such as defects, defect counts, test results and test status. Collects and
  analyses data for Test Data setup process evaluation and improvements, and integrates them into
  business processes to address the needs of the business.
- Doing various types of testing including system Testing, Integration Testing, Regression & Re-Testing,
   Performance Testing
- Reporting of bugs and preparation of test reports on daily basis.
- Verifying the detection & removal of bugs from the system.
- Requires code level changes and understanding of Complete solution architecture of Module.
- Worked in Verification & Validation, Quality Testing, Test Strategic Planning & Analysis to minimize
  risk to design and develop a business(Web) Solution in short timeframes (iterations that were typically
  over a 5-6-day period)

**Environment:** SQL server, Java, JSP, ActiveX Controls, Windows XP, XML, Oracle, MS Office (Word/Excel)

V Manage – A Web Based ERP system is based on a common database and a modular software design. The common database can allow every department of a business to store and retrieve information in real-time. The information should be reliable, Accessible, and easily shared. The modular software design means a business can select the modules they need, mix and match modules from different vendors, and add new modules of their own to improve

We have both the Offline as well as Online option to Manage and track all purchase registers, stock registers, and sales registers.

Business performance. Modules are as follows: Order Processing, Gate Entry Management, Admin Management, Challan Management, Inventory Management.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Create Test Plan and Test Cases.
- Requires code level changes and understanding of complete solution architecture of module.
- It is a server side application that requires changes in data through Java Servlets (JSPs).
- Deploy and creating manual testing for Project.
- Perform code level changes and deploy them in Development, Integration and finally to collaboration environment.
- Creating connections for JDBC and Data source.
- Responsible for creation of Test Status meeting, Test reports, Risk Analysis and Assessments, Traceability matrix.
- Responsible for preparation and delivery of Test execution and Defect management metrics.
- Provide inputs and sign-off on the Program Test Strategy, Integration and Acceptance Test Plan.
- Imparted training within team on the functionality of the application worked as Functional Lead and Back up Module Lead, prepared user manual for running the scripts and prepared presentation for team.

**Environment:** SQL server, Java, JSP, ActiveX Controls, Windows XP, XML, Oracle, MS Office (Word/Excel)